https://www.topendsports.com/privacy.htm

Home > Privacy
Privacy Statement /
Policy
At https://www.topendsports.com, the privacy of our visitors is of
extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of
personal information is received and collected by https://www.topendsports.com
and how it is used. If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy
policy, please feel free to contact us.
This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which the website Topend Sports (https://www.topendsports.com), herein referred to as the “Site”, collects data, uses this data, and maintains and discloses any collected information from Website users (herein referred to as “User”). Additionally, this policy applies to the entire Site and all the products and services offered by Topend Sports.
Definitions
Personal identifiable information – this is non-public information that is personally identifiable to you and obtained in order for us to provide you within our Website. Personal Identifiable Information may include, but not limited to, information such as your name, email address, and other related information that you provide to us or that we obtain about you.
Non-Personal identifiable information – “Non-Personal identifiable information” is information that is not personally identifiable to you and that we automatically collect when you access our Website with a web browser. It may also include, but not limited to, publicly available information that is shared between you and others.
Personal identifiable information
If a User visits our Site, we may collect personal identifiable information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our Site, register on the Site, place an order, subscribe to the newsletter, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously, but the User is entirely responsible for this by taking any necessary actions and/or precautions. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.
Non-personal identifiable information
If a User visits our Site, we may collect non-personal identifiable information about them during any visit. Non-personal identifiable information may include, but not limited to, the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the device, the operating system and the Internet service providers’ utilized and other likewise information.
Cookies
Our Website uses “Cookies” to identify the areas of our Website that you have visited. A Cookie is a small piece of data stored on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. We use Cookies to personalize the Content that you see on our Website. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of Cookies. However, if you disable Cookies, you may not be able to access functionality on our Website correctly or at all. We never place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.
The Topend Sports website may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. If the User wishes to refuse cookies, then they are entirely responsible to take the necessary actions/precautions when using the Site. In the event the User disables cookies on the Site, they should note that some parts of the Site may not function optimally or even properly.
How we use collected information
It should be understood that Topend Sports may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:
To improve the Site as a whole.
To improve/optimise Site performance and functionality
To improve customer service and relations.
To personalise any User experiences.
To understand how, why and what our Users view and interact with most.
User feedback may facilitate improving customer service requests and support.
To improve products and services.
To process payments and User requests.
To work with our afflitaes, sponsors and suppliers (“Partners”), including potential Partners, in order to improve the support and services offered to Users.
We may collect and use any information Users provide when, interacting, subscribing, and buying on the Site in order to improve the service to the User. However, we do not share or distribute this information with external non-auhtorised parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.
Emails
We may use any email addresses provided by the User to send information and updates relating to our services, products or partners. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If in any case the User decides to subscribe to wither our mailing list or as a paying member, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related products, service information from both Topend Sports and our related Partners. If at any time the User would like to stop receiving such emails, they retain full rights to do so and can by following the unsubscribe link located with the emails received. Alternatively, the User can always contact the Site directly and subscription removal will be arranged within a non-specific period of time.
Data Aggregation
We retain the right to collect and use any Non Personal Information collected from your use of our Website and aggregate such data for internal analytics that improve our Website and Service as well as for use or resale to others. At no time is your Personally Identifiable Information included in such data aggregations.
Sharing Information with Affiliates and Other Third Parties
We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your Personal Identifiable Information to third parties for marketing purposes. We may provide your Personal Identifiable Information to affiliates that provide services to us with regards to our Website (i.e. payment processors, Website hosting companies, etc.); such affiliates will only receive information necessary to provide the respective services and will be bound by confidentiality agreements limiting the use of such information.
Sharing your personal information
We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.
Privacy Policy Updates
Topend Sports reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. You should review this Privacy Policy frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we may notify you on our Website, by a blog post, by email, or by any method we determine. The method we chose is at our sole discretion. We will also change the “Last Updated” date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Any changes we make to our Privacy Policy are effective as of this Last Updated date and replace any prior Privacy Policies.
Visitors’ GDPR Rights
If you are within the European Union, you are entitled to certain information and have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation. Those rights include:
We will retain the any information you choose to provide to us until the earlier of: (a) you asking us to delete the information, (b) our decision to cease using our existing data providers, or (c) the Company decides that the value in retaining the data is outweighed by the costs of retaining it.
You have the right to request access to your data that the Company stores and the rights to either rectify or erase your personal data.
You have the right to seek restrictions on the processing of your data.
You have the right to object to the processing of your data and the right to the portability of your data.
To the extent that you provided consent to the Company’s processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based upon consent that occurred prior to your withdrawal of consent.
You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority that has jurisdiction over issues related to the General Data Protection Regulation.
We require only the information that is reasonably required to enter into a contract with you. We will not require you to provide consent for any unnecessary processing as a condition of entering into a contract with us.
Your acceptance of these terms
By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. If you choose to continue using the Site despite any disagreements you have with this policy, that choice resolves entirely with you and Topend Sports accepts no responsibility and is completely waved of all legal issues surrounding any issues/complaints.
Contacting us
If you have any issues, questions or comments concerning this privacy
policy, please contact us.
This policy was last updated on 18th May, 2018.
Search This Site
Topend Sports Extra
To keep up with the latest in sport science and this website, subscribe to our newsletter. We are also on facebook and twitter.
